<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Online Centre for Religious Studies on </title>
    <link>https://oc-rs.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Online Centre for Religious Studies on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oc-rs.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion and Worldviews | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2019/02/24/religion-and-worldviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2019/02/24/religion-and-worldviews/</guid>
      <description>Published in September 2018, the final report of the Commission on Religious Education - entitled Religion and Worldviews: the way forward - aimed to lay out a range of new ideas about how Religious Education can be approached in UK schools, following consultation with teachers, religious practitioners, and the public.
Religious Education in the UK is not the same as religious studies as taught in colleges and universities; the subject has a broader remit, contributing to pupils&amp;rsquo; spiritual, moral, social and cultural development, as well as personal well-being and community cohesion (DCSF, 2010).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language and Religion | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2019/02/18/language-and-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2019/02/18/language-and-religion/</guid>
      <description>If you want to learn about religious practices, philosophical concepts, or ways of living, you will almost certainly begin by looking for resources in your native language - this is the easiest way to engage with new ideas, and the quickest way to get an overview. Most religious principles and practices can be explained in any language with a reasonable degree of accuracy - but what if you want to learn more?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative perspectives in the study of religion | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2019/02/03/alternative-perspectives-in-the-study-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2019/02/03/alternative-perspectives-in-the-study-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>Alternative voices, due to their absence in mainstream texts and dismissal by historical scholars, are sometimes difficult to hear over the sound of traditional narratives &amp;ndash; but this is increasingly changing for the better. Where we can open ourselves to these voices, we can improve our understanding of the history of religion, but also our understanding of contemporary religious practitioners as well.
This blog post is a part of our online course Introduction to Religious Studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Misunderstandings About Religious Studies | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2018/12/20/common-misunderstandings-about-religious-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2018/12/20/common-misunderstandings-about-religious-studies/</guid>
      <description>Religious studies is the academic study of religion, this means that it involves careful and critical investigation, sympathetic understanding, and balanced opinions. However, there are plenty of misunderstandings about what religious studies means, or what it involves. Here are some of the &amp;lsquo;myths&amp;rsquo; that we&amp;rsquo;ve encountered&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s for priests / religious people This one seems to most frequently relate to a perception that religion = Christianity and religious studies = being a better Christian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why study religion? | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2018/12/07/why-study-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2018/12/07/why-study-religion/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re naturally curious about the world around us, and are drawn to things we find interesting; all of us will learn about something in our free time. It might be a new skill like crochet, web development, tennis, or horse riding; it might be the ins and outs of celebrity lives, footballer statistics, or political intrigue; and it might be an academic subject like geology, history, or&amp;hellip; religious studies.
But why religious studies?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Religion and Religious Truths | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2018/12/05/true-religion-and-religious-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2018/12/05/true-religion-and-religious-truths/</guid>
      <description>As practitioners of religious studies, academics are advised against investigating the truth claims of different religious traditions - it&amp;rsquo;s one of those awkward subjects that cannot be reliably studied (hence the ongoing difficulties integrating scientific empiricism with religious accounts of the world).
However, in a world full of competing truth claims, worldviews, and ways of living, the question inevitably sneaks in&amp;hellip; what does it mean that different prophets and sages make equally compelling arguments, accrue millions of followers, endure for thousands of years, yet offer no material proof?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dhikr in the Sufi Tradition | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2018/11/16/dhikr-in-the-sufi-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2018/11/16/dhikr-in-the-sufi-tradition/</guid>
      <description>In the centuries following the death of Muhammad, the Arabian peninsula was altered dramatically. The nomadic tribes, whose previous relationships had been mercurial and often violent, had become unified in a great empire, intended (at least by the devout) to reflect the great unity of Allah. Yet there were numerous difficulties in governing such a vast and culturally diverse area, not least of which was managing political power in accordance with Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The foundations of modern yoga | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2018/10/01/the-foundations-of-modern-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2018/10/01/the-foundations-of-modern-yoga/</guid>
      <description>We are faced with a difficult task when it comes to defining contemporary yoga, since there are numerous variants, countless schools, and a broad spectrum of teaching.
In Western nations such as the United Kingdom, it&amp;rsquo;s more likely to be found in health clubs and gyms, where the focus is placed upon the development of physical fitness and emotional stability. An example can be found on the official website of Iyengar Yoga (a variant of Hatha Yoga), which describes the benefits of their technique as “good health, mental peace, emotional equanimity and intellectual clarity” with no reference to the liberation of the purusha from prakriti, despite citing Patanjali’s ashtanga yoga as the original source of the wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literary bias in Celebrity Big Brother | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2018/08/25/literary-bias-in-celebrity-big-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2018/08/25/literary-bias-in-celebrity-big-brother/</guid>
      <description>One of the important parts of studying religion is to be open to observations all the time (even if you&amp;rsquo;re curled up watching TV).
On a recent episode of Celebrity Big Brother in the UK, two contestants were having a conversation about religion that caught our interest.
 Rodrigo: I heard that you are a Scientologist, is that right?
Kirstie: Yes
R: Can you tell me, what is it exactly? Because we see so much about it on the press, and there are so much controversy about it, and I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thematic approaches to the study of religion | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2018/07/19/thematic-approaches-to-the-study-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2018/07/19/thematic-approaches-to-the-study-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>There are, broadly speaking, two ways to approach religion as an academic subject.
The first is based on a sort of family tree model; it looks a bit like this.
 Religion ==Christianity ----Catholicism ----Eastern Orthodoxy ......Greek Orthodox Church ......Russian Orthodox Church ----Protestantism ......Methodism ......Evangelism  And so on.
It&amp;rsquo;s useful from a historical perspective, because we can easily trace back along a tradition&amp;rsquo;s lineage to see where it diverged from its closest neighbour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and faith - open source religion | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2017/11/24/freedom-and-faith-open-source-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2017/11/24/freedom-and-faith-open-source-religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion is often used as a by-word for rigid dogma and traditional patterns of behaviour, while open source is a technological term for freedom to examine, customise, and create without structure or restriction - however these different worlds actually have more in common than you might think.
The term ‘open source’ originates in the world of computer programming. It was coined in 1998 as part of an effort to promote the principles of collaborative development, and encourage businesses to share the source code for their projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of religious literacy | Blog | The Online Centre for Religious Studies</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/2017/11/08/the-importance-of-religious-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/2017/11/08/the-importance-of-religious-literacy/</guid>
      <description>Religion impacts many aspects of our lives, and religious events are all around us, both positive and negative. Over the last few years, the idea of improving religious literacy has been gaining ground, with the launch of the Religious Literacy Project at the Harvard Divinity School in 2015, and the publication of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Religious Education’s report (Improving Religious Literacy) in 2016.
But what is religious literacy, and how is it different to religious education, comparative religion, or religious studies?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://oc-rs.org/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oc-rs.org/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ` [outputs] home = [&amp;quot;HTML&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;JSON&amp;quot;] \`</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>